<speciesTraits_list>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Animal Handler</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Ride check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted, even if it is worse. Additionally, this character can make Persuasion checks to change the Attitude of an undomesticated creature that has an Intelligence score of 2 or lower.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>ride</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bellow</name>
        <description>As a Standard Action, this character can make a special attack roll (1d20 + its Character Level) and compare the result to the Fortitude Defense of all creatures and unattended objects in a 6-Square Cone. A successful hit deals 3d6 points of Sonic damage; if the attack misses, the target takes half damage instead.
            <br>Each use of this ability moves this character -1 step along the Condition Track.
            <br>This character can choose to add more dice (d6s) to the damage it deals with its Bellow, but each additional 1d6 of damage moves the character another -1 step along the Condition Track.</description>
        <type>attack</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Class Skill (Climb)</name>
        <description>This character treats the Climb skill as a Class Skill, regardless of Heroic Class.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Class Skill (Stealth)</name>
        <description>This character treats the Stealth skill as a Class Skill, regardless of Heroic Class.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Feat</name>
        <description>This character gains one bonus Feat at 1st level.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Feat (Improved Damage Threshold)</name>
        <description>This character gains Improved Damage Threshold as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Feat (Skill Focus)</name>
        <description>This character gains Skill Focus as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Feat (Toughness)</name>
        <description>This character gains Toughness as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Bonus Trained Skill</name>
        <description>This character chooses one additional Trained Skill at 1st level. The Skill must be chosen from their list of Class Skills.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Breathe Underwater</name>
        <description>This character can't drown in water.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Cold-Blooded</name>
        <description>This character takes a -5 penalty to their Fortitude Defense to resist Extreme Cold.</description>
        <type>defenses</type>
        <type>fortitude</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Gather Information))</name>
        <description>If this character has Gather Information as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Gather Information) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Initiative))</name>
        <description>If this character has Initiative as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Initiative) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Knowledge (Life Sciences)))</name>
        <description>If this character has Knowledge (Life Sciences) as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Knowledge (Life Sciences)) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Perception))</name>
        <description>If this character has Perception as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Perception) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Persuasion))</name>
        <description>If this character has Persuasion as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Persuasion) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Conditional Bonus Feat (Skill Focus (Survival))</name>
        <description>If this character has Survival as a Trained Skill, they gain Skill Focus (Survival) as a bonus Feat.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Cooperative</name>
        <description>This character automatically succeeds when attempting to Aid Another on a Skill Check, as long as the target is adjacent to, and can hear and understand, the character.</description>
        <type>special</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Damage Reduction 2</name>
        <description>This character possesses Damage Reduction 2.</description>
        <type>damageReduction</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Darkvision</name>
        <description>This character ignores Concealment (including Total Concealment) from darkness. However, they cannot perceive colors in total darkness.</description>
        <type>senses</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Deceptive</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Deception check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>deception</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Expert Pilot</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Pilot check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>pilot</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Expert Climber</name>
        <description>This character may choose to Take 10 on Climb checks even when distracted or threatened.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>climb</skill>
        <subtype>none</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Expert Swimmer</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Swim check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse. In addition, this character may choose to Take 10 on Swim checks, even when distracted or threatened.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>swim</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Extraordinary Recuperation</name>
        <description>This character regains Hit Points at double the normal rate.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Flash of Genius</name>
        <description>Once per encounter, this character can add a +5 circumstance bonus to to the result of one Knowledge, Mechanics, or Use Computer skill check.</description>
        <type>special</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Force Resistance</name>
        <description>This character receives a +5 bonus to their Will Defense against any use of the Use the Force skill.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Great Fortitude</name>
        <description>This character gains a +2 Species bonus to their Fortitude Defense.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Hold Breath</name>
        <description>This character gains a +2 Species bonus to their Fortitude Defense.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>endurance</skill>
        <subtype>none</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Heightened Awareness</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Perception check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>perception</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Intimidating Presence</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Persuasion check made to Intimidate others, but the result of the reroll must be accepted, even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>persuasion</skill>
        <subtype>none</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Intuitive Initiative</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Initiative check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>initiative</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Iron Will</name>
        <description>This character gains a +2 Species bonus to their Will Defense.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Keen Force Sense</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Use the Force check made to Search Your Feelings or Sense Force, keeping the better of the two results.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>useTheForce</skill>
        <subtype>none</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Lightning Reflexes</name>
        <description>This character gains a +2 Species bonus to their Reflex Defense.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Limb Regeneration</name>
        <description>This character regrows a lost limb in 1d10 days. At the end of that time, all Persistent Conditions associated with the loss of the limb are removed.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Logical Reasoning</name>
        <description>This character can use their Intelligence modifier in place of their Charisma modifier on Persuasion checks.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Low-Light Vision</name>
        <description>This character ignores Concealment (but not Total Concealment) from darkness.</description>
        <type>senses</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Natural Armor (+1)</name>
        <description>This character receives a +1 Natural Armor bonus to their Reflex Defense. A Natural Armor bonus stacks with an Armor bonus.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Natural Armor (+2)</name>
        <description>This character receives a +2 Natural Armor bonus to their Reflex Defense. A Natural Armor bonus stacks with an Armor bonus.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Natural Weapons</name>
        <description>When this character makes an Unarmed attack, it may choose to use its Natural Weapons, dealing 1d6 points of Slashing damage with the attack instead of normal Unarmed damage. This character is always considered armed with their Natural Weapons.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Poison</name>
        <description>If the Natural Weapons of this character deals damage to a living target, the target is also Poisoned. If the Poison succeeds on an attack roll (1d20 + the character's Character Level) against the target's Fortitude Defense, the target moves -1 step along the Condition Track.
            <br>A target moved to the end of the Condition Track by the Poison is Immobilized, but not Unconscious.</description>
        <type>attack</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Primitive</name>
        <description>This character does not gain Weapon Proficiency (Heavy Weapons), Weapon Proficiency (Pistols), or Weapon Proficiency (Rifles) as starting Feats at first level, even if their Class normally grants them.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Rage</name>
        <description>Once per day, this character can fly into a Rage as a Swift Action. While Raging, this character temporarily gains a +2 Rage bonus on melee attack rolls and melee damage rolls, but cannot use Skills that require patience and concentration, such as Mechanics, Stealth, or Use the Force. A fit of Rage lasts for a number of rounds equal to 5 + the character's Constitution modifier.
            <br>At the end of its Rage, the character moves -1 Persistent step along the Condition Track. The penalties imposed by this Persistent Condition persist until the character takes at least 10 minutes to recuperate, during which time the character can't engage in any strenuous activity.</description>
        <type>special</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Reactive Claw</name>
        <description>Once per encounter when this character damages an opponent with a melee attack, they can make a single melee attack with their Natural Weapons against that target as a Swift Action. This character must have one hand free at the time to make this attack (and thus cannot be wielding a two-handed weapon).</description>
        <type>attack</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Scent</name>
        <description>At close range (within 10 squares), this character ignores Concealment and Cover for purposes of Perception checks, and takes no penalty from poor visibility while Tracking.</description>
        <type>senses</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Sneaky</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Stealth check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>stealth</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Special Equipment (Antiox Breath Mask)</name>
        <description>Without protective goggles, this character is considered Blind. Without an Antiox Breath Mask, this character begins to Suffocate. A replacement mask costs 2,000 credits (500 on Dorin), and a year's supply of filters costs 200 credits (50 on Dorin). This character begins play with these items at no cost.
            <br>An Antiox Breath Mask is poisonous to other Species.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Supreme Stability</name>
        <description>This character is completely immune to being knocked Prone.</description>
        <type>defenses</type>
        <subtype>none</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Sneaky</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Persuasion check, keeping the better of the two results.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>persuasion</skill>
        <subtype>highReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Survival Instinct</name>
        <description>This character may choose to reroll any Survival check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted even if it is worse.</description>
        <type>skill</type>
        <skill>survival</skill>
        <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Superior Defenses</name>
        <description>This character gain a +1 Species bonus to all their Defenses.</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Weapon Familiarity (Arg'garok)</name>
        <description>This character treats the Arg'garok as an Advanced Melee Weapon, instead of an Exotic Weapons (Melee).</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Weapon Familiarity (Bowcaster and Ryyk Blade)</name>
        <description>This character treats the Bowcaster as a Rifle instead of an Exotic Weapon (Ranged). They additionally treat the Ryyk Blade as an Advanced Melee Weapon instead of an Exotic Weapon (Melee).</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
    <speciesTrait>
        <name>Weapon Familiarity (Gungan Weaponry)</name>
        <description>This character treats the Atlatl, Cesta, and Electropole as Simple Weapons (Melee) instead of Exotic Weapons (Melee).</description>
        <type>none</type>
    </speciesTrait>
</speciesTraits_list>