<talents_list>
    <jedi_talents>
        <jediConsular>
            <talent>
                <name>Adept Negotiator</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>As a Standard Action, you can weaken the resolve of one opponent with your words. The target must have an Intelligence of 3 or higher, and it must be able to see, hear, and understand you. Make a Persuasion check; if the result equals or exceeds the target's Will Defense, it moves -1 step along the Condition Track. The target gets a +5 bonus to its Will Defense if it is higher level than you.
                    <br>If the target reaches the end of its Condition Track, it does not fall unconscious, instead, it cannot attack you or your allies for the remainder of the encounter unless you or one of your allies attacks it or one of its allies first. This is a Mind-Affecting effect.
                    <br>You affect the Condition Track of the specific character (usually the Vehicle's Commander), not a Starship.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Force Persuasion</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You can use your Use the Force modifier instead of your Persuasion check modifier when making a Persuasion check. You are considered Trained in the Persuasion skill. If you are entitled to a Persuasion check reroll, you may reroll your Use the Force check instead (subject to the same circumstances and limitations).</description>
                <type>skill</type>
                <skill>persuasion</skill>
                <subtype>replacement</subtype>
                <replacement>useTheForce</replacement>
                <prerequisites>Adept Negotiator</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Master Negotiator</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>If you successfully use the Adept Negotiator Talent, your target moves an additional -1 step along the Condition Track. This is a Mind-Affecting effect. You affect the Condition Track of the specific character (usually the Vehicle's Commander), not a Starship.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>Adept Negotiator</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Skilled Advisor</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You can spend a Full-Round Action advising an ally, thereby granting them a +5 bonus on their next Skill Check. If you spend a Force Point, the bonus increases to +10. The target must be able to (and willing) to hear and understand your voice. You cannot advise yourself. This is a Mind-Affecting effect.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
        </jediConsular>
    </jedi_talents>
    <noble_talents>
        <influence>
            <talent>
                <name>Presence</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You can make a Persuasion check to Intimidate a creature as a Standard Action (instead of a Full-Round Action).</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Demand Surrender</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Once per encounter, you can make a Persuasion check as a Standard Action to demand surrender from an opponent who has been reduced to one-half or less of its hit points. If your check result equals or exceeds the target's Will Defense, it surrenders to you and your allies, drops any weapons it is holding, and takes no hostile actions. If the target is higher level than you, it gains a +5 bonus to its Will Defense. If you or any of your allies attack it, it no longer submits to your will and can act normally. You can only use this Talent against a particular target once per encounter. This is a Mind-Affecting effect.
                    <br>Unlike other Mind-Affecting effects, you need only to hail a Vehicle to Demand Surrender. You can demand surrender of a vehicle that has been reduced to one-half or fewer of its hit points, even if the crew is uninjured. You make your check against the Vehicle's Commander; all Nonheroic crews are assumed to have a Will Defense of 10. If the CL of the target Vehicle is greater than your Heroic Level or the CL of your Vehicle, the target gains a +5 bonus to its Will Defense. You can't use this Talent to Demand Surrender from a Vehicle that is more than one size larger than yours under any circumstances- Star Destroyers don't surrender to X-Wings.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>Presence</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Improved Weaken Resolve</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Once per round, when you deal damage equal to or greater than the target's Damage Threshold, you can make a Persuasion check as a Free Action; if the result equals or exceeds the target's Will Defense, you fill the target with terror, causing it to flee from you at top speed for 1 minute. The target can't take Standard Actions, Swift Actions, or Full-Round Actions while fleeing. As a Free Action or Reaction, the target can spend a Force Point (if it has not already spent one earlier in the round) to negate the effect. The effect is automatically negated if the target's level is equal to or higher than your Character Level. This is a Mind-Affecting fear effect.
                    <br>Unlike with other Mind-Affecting effects, you need only to hail a Vehicle to weaken the crew's resolve. When you deal damage that equals or exceeds a Vehicle's Damage Threshold, you may use this Talent; in addition, you may Ready an Action to use this Talent after any Gunner on your Vehicle deals damage that equals or exceeds a Vehicle's Damage Threshold. You make your check against the Vehicle's Commander; all Nonheroic crews are assumed to have a Will Defense of 10. The effect is automatically negated if the target Vehicle's Challenge Level is greater than your Heroic Level or your Vehicle's Challenge Level.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>Presence,Weaken Resolve</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Weaken Resolve</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Once per round, when you deal damage equal to or greater than the target's Damage Threshold, you can make a Persuasion check as a Free Action; if the result equals or exceeds the target's Will Defense, you fill the target with terror, causing it to flee from you at top speed for 1 minute. The target can't take Standard Actions, Swift Actions, or Full-Round Actions while fleeing, but the target stops fleeing and can act normally if it is wounded. As a Free Action or Reaction, the target can spend a Force Point (if it has not already spent one earlier in the round) to negate the effect. The effect is automatically negated if the target's level is equal to or higher than your Character Level. This is a Mind-Affecting fear effect.
                    <br>Unlike with other Mind-Affecting effects, you need only to hail a Vehicle to weaken the crew's resolve. When you deal damage that equals or exceeds a Vehicle's Damage Threshold, you may use this Talent; in addition, you may Ready an Action to use this Talent after any Gunner on your Vehicle deals damage that equals or exceeds a Vehicle's Damage Threshold. You make your check against the Vehicle's Commander; all Nonheroic crews are assumed to have a Will Defense of 10. The effect is automatically negated if the target Vehicle's Challenge Level is greater than your Heroic Level or your Vehicle's Challenge Level.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>Presence</prerequisites>
            </talent>
        </influence>
    </noble_talents>
    <scoundrel_talents>
        <fortune>
            <talent>
                <name>Fool's Luck</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>As a Standard Action, you can spend a Force Point to gain one of the following benefits for the rest of the encounter:
                    <br>-+1 competence bonus to attack rolls
                    <br>-+5 competence bonus on Skill Checks
                    <br>-+1 competence bonus to all your Defenses</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Fortune's Favor</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Whenever you score a Critical Hit with a melee or ranged attack, you gain a free Standard Action. You must take the extra Standard Action before the end of your turn, or else it is lost.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Gambler</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You gain a +2 competence bonus on Wisdom checks when you Gamble. You can select this Talent multiple times; each time you take this Talent, the competence bonus increases by +2.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Knack</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Once per day, you can reroll a Skill Check and take the better result. You can select this Talent multiple times; each time you select this Talent, you can use it one additional time per day.</description>
                <type>special</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Lucky Shot</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Once per day, you can reroll an attack roll and take the better result. You can select this Talent multiple times; each time you select this Talent, you can use it one additional time per day.</description>
                <type>attack</type>
                <prerequisites>Knack</prerequisites>
            </talent>
        </fortune>
    </scoundrel_talents>
    <scout_talents>
        <awareness>
            <talent>
                <name>Acute Senses</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You may reroll any Perception check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted, even if it is worse. This Talent applies to Use Computer checks made to perceive enemy ships.</description>
                <type>skill</type>
                <skill>perception</skill>
                <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Expert Tracker</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You take no penalty on Survival checks made to Follow Tracks while moving your normal Speed.</description>
                <type>speed</type>
                <prerequisites>Acute Senses</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Improved Initiative</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You may choose to reroll any Initiative check, but the result of the reroll must be accepted, even if it is worse.</description>
                <type>skill</type>
                <skill>initiative</skill>
                <subtype>lowReroll</subtype>
                <prerequisites>Acute Senses</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Keen Shot</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You take no penalty on your attack roll when attacking a target with Concealment (but not Total Concealment).</description>
                <type>attack</type>
                <prerequisites>Acute Senses</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Uncanny Dodge I</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You retain your Dexterity bonus to your Reflex Defense regardless of being caught Flat-Footed or struck by a hidden attacker. You still lose your Dexterity bonus to your Reflex Defense if you are Immobilized.
                    <br>If you are the Pilot, this Talent applies to your Vehicle.</description>
                <type>defenses</type>
                <subtype>none</subtype>
                <prerequisites>Acute Senses,Improved Initiative</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Uncanny Dodge II</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>You cannot be Flanked. You can react to opponents on opposite sides of you as easily as you can react to a single attacker.
                    <br>If you are the Pilot, this Talent applies to your Vehicle.</description>
                <type>defenses</type>
                <subtype>none</subtype>
                <prerequisites>Acute Senses,Improved Initiative,Uncanny Dodge I</prerequisites>
            </talent>
        </awareness>
    </scout_talents>
    <soldier_talents>
        <armorSpecialist>
            <talent>
                <name>Armor Mastery</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>The maximum Dexterity bonus of your Armor improves by +1. You must be proficient with the Armor you are wearing to gain this benefit.</description>
                <type>none</type>
                <prerequisites>Armored Defense</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Armored Defense</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>When calculating your Reflex Defense, you may add either your Heroic Level or your Armor bonus, whichever is higher. You must be proficient with the Armor you are wearing to gain this benefit.</description>
                <type>none</type>
                <prerequisites>none</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Improved Armored Defense</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>When calculating your Reflex Defense, you may add your Heroic Level plus one-half your Armor bonus (rounded down), or your Armor bonus, whichever is higher. You must be proficient with the Armor you are wearing to gain this benefit.</description>
                <type>none</type>
                <prerequisites>Armored Defense</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Juggernaut</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>Your Armor does not reduce your Speed or the distance you can move while Running. You must be proficient with the Armor you are wearing to gain this benefit.</description>
                <type>speed</type>
                <prerequisites>Armored Defense</prerequisites>
            </talent>
            <talent>
                <name>Second Skin</name>
                <source>CR</source>
                <description>When wearing Armor with which you are proficient, your Armor bonus to your Reflex Defense and Equipment bonus to your Fortitude Defense each increases by +1.</description>
                <type>none</type>
                <prerequisites>Armored Defense</prerequisites>
            </talent>
        </armorSpecialist>
    </soldier_talents>
</talents_list>